Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Course Bulletins MC.286
New York University Archives
- College of Dentistry (RG 25), 1865-1984, April 2014-ongoing
  - College of Dentistry Academic Bulletin, May 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Academic bulletin for College of Dentistry. Includes program information for the DDS program, Dental Hygiene programs, advanced education programs, master's degree programs, certificate program in clinical research, programs for international dentists, and the Linhart Continuing Dental Education program.
- College of Dentistry - Post-Graduate Division (RG 25.1), 1926-2002
  - Bulletins, 1926-1932, 1934-1943, 1947-1956, 1957-1959 (Box 88)
  - Bulletins, 1959-1978, 1988-1990, 2002 (Box 89)
- Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development (RG 26), 1888-2015, April 2014-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1888-1891, 1901-1905, 1914-1915 (Box 90)
  - Bulletins, 1900-1921 (Box 203)
  - Bulletins and related materials, 1914-1916, 1922-1942 (Box 91)
    Includes the Institute of Education.
  - Bulletins, 1921-1930 (Box 92)
  - Bulletins, 1923-1934 (Box 93)
  - Bulletins, 1931-1935 (Box 94)
  - Bulletins, 1934-1939 (Box 95)
  - Bulletins - Summer Session and Intersession, 1940-1946 (Box 201)
  - Bulletins, 1938-1941 (Box 96)
  - Bulletins, 1940-1946 (Box 97)
  - Bulletins, 1940-1949, 1952-1953 (Box 98)
    Includes Department of Dramatic Art (1952-1953).
  - Bulletins, 1946-1951 (Box 204)
  - Bulletins, 1951-1953 (Box 205)
  - Methods of Techniques in Social Recreation 180.298 syllabus, Spring 1954 (Box 91)
  - Bulletins, 1954-1955, 1959-1969 (Box 99)
  - Bulletins, 1955-1960 (Box 204)
  - Bulletins, 1969-1976 (Box 100)
  - Bulletins, 1977-1980 (Box 101)
  - Bulletins, 1980-1983 (Box 102)
  - Bulletins, 1983-1987 (Box 103)
  - Bulletins, 1987-1992 (Box 104)
  - Bulletins, 1992-1997 (Box 105)
  - Bulletins, 1996-2004 (Box 106)
  - Bulletins, 2003-2008 (Box 107)
  - Bulletins, 2008-2011 (Box 108)
  - Undergraduate Bulletins (PDFs), 2003-2014; cuid17991 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Graduate Bulletins (PDFs), 2005-2015; cuid17992 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Steinhardt School Bulletin, April 2014-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Steinhardt offers undergraduate, master's, advanced certificate, and doctoral degree programs in applied psychology, the visual and performing arts and arts professions, education, health, and media. Undergraduate programs combine inquiry in the liberal arts and sciences, mastery of a specific field of study, global study, and applied learning, internship, and other fieldwork experiences. Graduate programs range from those that emphasize advanced research and scholarship to those that prepare students for advanced professional practice and leadership. Many graduate programs are interdisciplinary and include unique opportunities for global learning and research.
  - Steinhardt School Courses, May 2014-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website containing course listings for Steinhardt school-wide courses, including liberal arts CORE classes and interdisciplinary honors and seminars. The website also lists courses by departments; the departments include Administration, Leadership, and Technology; Applied Psychology; Art and Art Professions; Communicative Sciences and Disorders; Applied Statistics, Social Science, and Humanities; Media, Culture, and Communication; Music and Performing Arts Professions; Nutrition and Food Studies; Occupational Therapy; Physical Therapy; and Teaching and Learning.
  - Steinhardt School 2016-2018 Undergraduate Bulletin, October 2016-February 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    Steinhardt School undergraduate bulletin for the 126th and 127th sessions. The bulletin contains policies, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of the school and its departments and programs.
  - Steinhardt School Graduate Bulletin, November 2017-June 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Steinhardt graduate bulletin for 2017-2019.
  - Steinhardt School Undergraduate 2018-2020 Bulletin, February-June 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the 2018-2020 undergraduate Bulletin for the Steinhardt School. Bulletin contains the policies, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of the school and its departments and programs.
  - Steinhardt School Graduate Bulletin 2017-2019, October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development Graduate Bulletin 2017-2019, which lists information about admissions, registration, departmental overviews, individual departments, and course listings.
  - Steinhardt School Bulletin 2018-2020, October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development Undergraduate Bulletin 2018-2020, which lists information about admissions, registration, departmental overviews, individual departments, and course listings.
  - Steinhardt School Bulletin, March 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    PDFs of the undergraduate and graduate Steinhardt bulletins dating back to 2015.
- Stern School of Business (Undergraduate) (RG 27), 1900-2015
  - Bulletins, 1900-1913 (Box 205)
  - Bulletins and Programs, 1906-1907, 1912-1916, 1920-1921, 1923-1924, 1927-1935 (Box 109)
    Includes copies of addresses delivered under the Don R. Mellett Memorial Fund for the Department of Journalism (1931-1935).
  - Bulletins, 1913-1921 (Box 205)
  - Bulletins, 1921-1926 (Box 205)
  - Bulletins, 1926-1933 (Box 206)
  - Programs, 1928-1929 (Box 207)
  - Programs, 1929-1930 (Box 207)
  - Programs, 1930-1931 (Box 207)
  - Programs, 1931-1932 (Box 207)
  - Programs, 1932-1933 (Box 207)
  - Programs, 1933-1934 (Box 207)
  - Bulletins, 1933-1941 (Box 206)
  - Programs, 1934-1935 (Box 207)
  - Bulletins and Programs, 1934-1963 (Box 110)
  - Programs, 1935-1936 (Box 207)
  - Programs, 1936-1937 (Box 207)
  - Programs, 1937-1938 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1938-1939 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1939-1940 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1940-1941 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1941-1942 (Box 209)
  - Bulletins, 1941-1949 (Box 206)
  - Programs, 1942-1943 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1943-1944 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1944-1945 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1945-1946 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1946-1947 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1947-1948 (Box 209)
  - Programs, 1948-1949 (Box 209)
  - Bulletins, 1949-1955 (Box 206)
  - Bulletins, 1955-1962 (Box 207)
  - Bulletins, 1962-1963 (Box 207)
  - Bulletins and Programs, 1963-1972 (Box 111)
  - Bulletins and Programs, 1972-1985 (Box 112)
  - Bulletins and Programs, 1984-1998 (Box 113)
  - Bulletins and Programs, 1998-2010 (Box 114)
  - Bulletin (PDF), 2013-2015; cuid17993 (Box Electronic Records)
- Stern School of Business (Graduate) (RG 28), 1916-2016
  - Graduate School of Business Administration Bulletins, 1916-1917, 1919-1931 (Box 210, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1918-1921, 1940-1941, 1945-1946, 1950-1951, 1952-1953, 1954-1955, 1959-1979 (Box 115)
    Includes Summer School bulletins (1959-1963).
  - Bulletins, 1931-1944 (Box 208)
  - Bulletins, 1945-1953 (Box 208)
  - Bulletins, 1955-1963 (Box 208)
  - Bulletins, 1963-1971 (Volume RG28 Bulletins - Bound 1963-1971)
  - Bulletins, 1972-1978 (Volume RG28 Bulletins - Bound 1972-1978)
  - Bulletins, 1979-1985 (Box 116)
  - Bulletins, 1985-1991 (Box 117)
  - Bulletins, 1993-1999, 2001-2002 (Box 118)
  - Bulletins, 2002-2005, 2008-2010 (Box 119)
  - Bulletins (PDFs), 2000-2016; cuid17994 (Box Electronic Records)
- School of Commerce, Accounts and Finance - Wall Street Division (RG 28.9), 1915-1940
  - Bulletins, 1915-1916, 1917-1919, 1920-1940 (Box 120)
- School of Retailing/Institute of Retail Management (RG 30), 1922-1978
  - Bulletins, 1922-1948 (Box 208)
  - Bulletins, 1948-1963 (Box 209)
  - Bulletins, 1919, 1922-1923, 1925-1927, 1928-1933, 1934-1941, 1955-1958 (Box 121)
    Includes proposed course of study for Training School for Teachers of Retail Selling (1919).
  - Bulletins, 1959-1978 (Box 122)
- School of Architecture and Allied Arts (RG 31), 1926-1941
  - Fine Arts and Architecture Bulletins, 1926-1939 (Box 210, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1929-1935, 1940-1941 (Box 123)
- School of Professional Studies (RG 32), 1903-ongoing
  Includes Extramural Divisions, Extension Divisions, and Division of General Education.
  - Bulletins, 1903-1904, 1916-1941 (Box 124)
  - Bulletins, 1934-1941, 1952-1957 (Box 125)
  - Bulletins - Course for Adults, 1950 (Volume RG32 Bulletins - Bound 1950)
  - Bulletins - Course for Adults, 1951 (Volume RG32 Bulletins - Bound 1951)
  - Bulletins - Course for Adults, 1952 (Volume RG32 Bulletins - Bound 1952)
  - Bulletins, 1958-1959, 1961-1965, 1967-1970 (Box 126)
  - Bulletins - Courses Open to the Public, 1965-1967 (Volume RG32 Bulletins - Bound 1965-1967)
  - Bulletins - Courses Open to the Public, 1967-1969 (Volume RG32 Bulletins - Bound 1967-1969)
  - Bulletins, 1971-1973 (Box 127)
  - Bulletins, 1974-1976 (Box 128)
  - Bulletins, 1977-1979 (Box 129)
  - Bulletins, 1979-1980 (Box 130)
  - Bulletins, 1981-1982 (Box 131)
  - Bulletins, 1983-1984 (Box 132)
  - Bulletins, 1984-1986 (Box 133)
  - Bulletins, 1986-1988 (Box 134)
  - Bulletins, 1988-1990 (Box 135)
  - Diploma in Bank Lending, Concentration in Credit Analysis, 1990-1991 (Box 135)
  - Bulletins, 1990-1992, 1994-1996 (Box 136)
  - Bulletins, 1992-1995 (Box 137)
  - Bulletins, 1996-1998 (Box 138)
  - Bulletins, 1998-1999 (Box 139)
  - Bulletins, 1999-2000 (Box 140)
  - Bulletins, 2000-2001 (Box 141)
  - Bulletins, 2002-2003 (Box 142)
  - Bulletins, 2003-2004 (Box 143)
  - Bulletins, 2005-2007 (Box 144)
  - Bulletins, 2007-2009 (Box 145)
  - Bulletins, 2009-2010, 2012, 2014 (Box 146)
  - Bulletins, 2015 (Box 147)
  - School of Continuing and Professional Studies Bulletin, April 2014-August 2018 (Box Electronic Records)
    This website contains the SCPS bulletins from Summer 2014 to Fall 2015. Program areas covered include Applied Politics, Business, Creative Cities and Economic Development, Global Affairs, Health and Care Programs, Hospitality and Tourism, Languages and Humanities, Media Industry Studies and Design, Philanthropy and Fundraising, Real Estate, and Sports Management, Media, and Business.
  - School of Professional Studies Degree Programs, October 2018-February 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    Information on the undergraduate, graduate, and online programs at the School of Professional Studies.
  - School of Professional Studies Career Advancement Courses, October 2018-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    A website detailing course offerings from the School of Professional Studies (RG 32).
  - School of Professional Studies Divisions and Departments, August 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website listing the divisions and departments in NYUSPS. NYUSPS is made up the Center for Applied Liberal Arts, Center for Global Affairs, Center for Publishing, Division of Applied Undergraduate Studies, Division of Programs in Business, English Language Institute, Jonathan M. Tisch Center of Hospitality, Preston Robert Tisch Institute for Global Sport, and the Schack Institute of Real Estate. Each division is divided into programs, which consists of degree details containing course descriptions for required and elective courses for each degree.
  - School of Professional Studies Academics, August 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Landing page detailing programs and degrees associated with NYUSPS.
  - School of Professional Studies Master's Degrees, August 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    This page details master's degree programs offered by the NYU School of Professional Studies, with links to individual programs where users can find information about admissions requirements, course listings and degree requirements, financing information, and general structural information about the program. Programs include an MS in Construction Management, MS in Event Management, MS in Global Affairs, MS in Global Security Conflict and Cyber Crime (STEM), MS in Global Sport, MS in Hospitality Industry Studies, MS in Human Capital Analytics and Technology (STEM), MS in Human Resource Management and Development, MS in Integrated Marketing, MS in Management and Systems (STEM), MS in Professional Writing, MS in Project Management (STEM), MS in Public Relations and Corporate Communication, MS in Publishing, MS in Real Estate, MS in Real Estate Development, MS in Sports Business, MS in Tourism Management, and MS in Translation.
  - School of Professional Studies Bachelor's Degrees, August 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    This page contains information about the bachelor's degree programs offered by NYU's School of Professional Studies, and features navigable links to pages describing each degree program individually, including admissions requirements, coursework and degree requirements, and financing options. Programs include BS in Hotel and Tourism Management, BS in Real Estate, BS in Sports Management, BS in Applied Data Analytics and Visualization, BA in Applied General Studies, BS in Digital Communications and Media, BA in Social Sciences, BS in Leadership and Management Studies, BS in Information Systems Management, BS in Real Estate, BA in Humanities, BS in Marketing Analytics, and BS in Healthcare Management.
  - School of Professional Studies Associate Degrees, August 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of associate degrees programs at the School of Professional Studies, including descriptions and degree requirements for individual programs, as well as admissions criteria and financing information. Associate degrees include an AAS in Business, AA in Liberal Arts, AAS in Health Administration, and AAS in Information Systems Management.
  - School of Professional Studies Online Degree Programs, August 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    This page details the online degree programs offered by NYU's School of Professional Studies. There are links to individual degree program pages that include information about those programs' degree requirements, courses, admissions criteria, career outlooks, and financing options. Online programs include an MS in Global Sport, MS in Human Capital Analytics and Technology (STEM), MS in Human Resource Management and Development, MS in Professional Writing, MS in Project Management (STEM), MS in Translation, BA in Social SCiences, and a BS in Leadership and Management Studies.
  - School of Professional Studies Degree Directory, August 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Online course directory for the NYU School of Professional Studies. The website is broken down by area of study, degree program, and department. Each degree listed can include an overview of the degree, program structure, program requirements, admission criteria, program flexibility, and financial aid. The core requirements and concentration sections links to full course descriptions for classes in each degree.
- School of Professional Studies - American Language Institute for International Students (RG 32.1), 1964-1976
  - Bulletins, 1964-1965, 1967-1971, 1974-1976 (Box 148)
- School of Professional Studies - Real Estate Institute (RG 32.3), 1970-1993
  - Bulletins, 1970-1971, 1974-1988 (Box 149)
  - Bulletins, 1988-1997, 2000-2001 (Box 150)
  - Bulletins, 1992-1993 (Box 137)
- School of Professional Studies - Paul McGhee Division (RG 32.12), 1985-2012
  - Bulletins, 1985-1992 (Box 151)
  - Bulletins, 1992-2001 (Box 152)
  - Bulletins, 2000-2012 (Box 153)
- School of Professional Studies - General Studies Program (RG 32.13), 1979-1992
  - Bulletins, 1979-1983, 1991-1992 (Box 154)
- Paterson Collegiate Center (RG 32.40), 1926-1932
  - Bulletins, 1926-1932 (Box 184)
- Newark Institute of Arts and Sciences (RG 32.41), 1915-1916
  - Announcements, 1915-1916 (Box 184)
- Westchester County Centers (RG 32.42), 1928-1931
  - Bulletins, 1928-1931 (Box 184)
- Hempstead Center (RG 32.43), 1930-1931
  - Bulletins, 1930-1931 (Box 184)
- Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service (RG 33), 1938-2011, April 2014-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1938-1944, 1947-1963 (Box 155)
  - Bulletins, 1963-1982 (Box 156)
  - Bulletins, 1982-1995 (Box 157)
  - Bulletins, 1996-2011 (Box 158)
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Courses, April 2014-October 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    The Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service offers curricula covering domestic and international issues including nonprofit management, financial management, public policy analysis, urban public policy studies, urban planning, and health policy and management. Masters and doctoral degree programs are offered on both full-time and part-time bases. The Advanced Professional Certificate Programs and the Master of Science in Management Program offer career development opportunities for experienced professionals.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Hunger and Food Security in a Global Perspective, May 2014-July 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course description and syllabi for the Hunger and Food Security in a Global Perspective course in Accra, Ghana at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Urbanization and Sustainable Development in a Transitional Economy: Experiencing China, May 2014-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course description and syllabi for the Urbanization and Sustainable Development in a Transitional Economy: Experiencing China course in Shanghai, China at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Bulletin, October 2016-November 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Graduate School of Public Service bulletin for 2015-2017.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Courses, May 2017-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website containing course information for Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service. It includes course highlights, courses across NYU that can be taken as pre-approved electives, courses abroad, capstone information, independent study, non-Wagner student enrollment in Wagner courses, program requirement checklists, course evaluations, skills workshops, and undergraduate and graduate course schedules by semester. Each semester since Fall 2017 Wagner featured course highlights, linking to descriptions of new courses, returning courses not taught the previous year, courses that require application, courses with intensive format, saturday courses, courses with new titles, and courses with new instructors.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Nonprofit Governance, July 2017-June 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course description and syllabi for the Nonprofit Governance course at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Transformative Participation for Democratic Practice, July 2017-August 2018 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course description and syllabi for the Transformative Participation for Democratic Practice course at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Courses, August 2018-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Listing of all course descriptions for NYU Wagner.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Degree Programs, August 2018-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Information on the following graduate degree programs at Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service: Master of Public Administration-Public & Nonprofit Management & Policy; Master of Public Administration-Health Policy & Management; Master of Urban Planning; Master of Science in Public Policy; Executive Master of Public Administration; PhD in Public Administration; Online Master of Health Administration; and global Executive MPA: Joint degree with UCL. Specific degree program pages focus on specializations, tracks, coursework, degree requirements and faculty.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Courses, March 2019-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    Listing of all course descriptions for Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service.
  - Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Bulletin, October 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Bulletin for the Robert F. Wagner Graduate School of Public Service. Includes general admission requirements; description and requirements of academic programs for the Master of Public Administration, Health Policy and Management, Master of Urban Planning, Online Master of Health Administration, Master of Science in Public Policy, PhD in Public Administration, dual-degree programs, and undergraduate offerings. Also includes course listings, library and program-related facilities, academic calendar, cost of attendance, and financial assistance.
  - Master of Science in Health Law and Strategy Curriculum, February 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Semester by semester course descriptions for the Master of Science in Health Law and Strategy, a joint program of NYU Law and NYU Wagner.
- Silver School of Social Work (RG 34), 1960-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1960-1986 (Box 159)
  - Bulletins, 1986-2010 (Box 160)
  - Bulletin (PDF), 2013-2014; cuid17995 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Silver School of Social Work Bulletin, April 2014-May 2015 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Silver School bulletin for 2013-2014.
  - Silver School of Social Work PhD Curriculum, September 2016-March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Webpage detailing the program requirements and curriculum content for the PhD in Social Work at the Silver School.
  - Silver School of Social Work Bachelor of Science Course Descriptions, September 2016-March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course descriptions of required and elective courses for the Bachelor of Science at the Silver School of Social Work.
  - Silver School of Social Work Master of Social Work Course Descriptions, September 2016-March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website featuring course descriptions for the Master of Social Work at the Silver School. From 2016-2017, the course descriptions are organized by first year (Professional Foundation) courses, second year (Advanced Concentration in Clinical Practice), and electives. In 2018, the name of the requirements of the Master's changed and are organized by first year (Generalist Practice), Second Year (Specialized Practice), three-credit electives, and one credit electives.
  - Silver School of Social Work Student Manuals and Community Standards, September 2016-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDFs of the BS Student Manual, MSW Student Manual, PhD Student Manual, DSW Student Manual, Silver School Academic Bulletin, and the Silver School of Social Work Credit Hour Policy.
  - Silver School of Social Work Academics, September 2016-May 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Landing page for the Silver school academics program containing program student manuals for the Bachelor of Science, Master of Social Work, PhD, Doctorate in Clinical Social Work programs, as well as the credit hour policy and academic bulletin for 2015-2017
  - Silver School of Social Work Study Abroad, October 2016-March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course listings for Silver School's study abroad courses. Contains information for MSW and semester programs at study abroad sites as well as single course offerings for 2017-2020.
  - Silver School of Social Work Bulletin, August 2018-March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Silver School bulletin for 2017-2019.
  - Silver School of Social Work Master of Social Work, June 2020-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)